Guide to the United Federation of Teachers Records WAG.022
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series X: Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 16 websites in 16 archived websites.
  The YouTube channel for UFT includes videos on COVID-19 vaccinations, COVID-19 updates for the union, teacher union day, awards, paid parental leave, UFT's Bill de Blasio endorsement for mayor, teacher evaluation agreement, universal free lunch in New York City public schools, #EdWalk march to Albany on school funding, pride event on the Pulse shooting in Orlando, community learning schools, Friedrichs v. California Teachers Association, #ProtectOurSchools Coalition rally, Alliance for Quality Education, state budget hearings, classroom supplies, Health and Vision Center, Reclaim the Promise of Public Education day of action, emergency educational action plan, charter schools, and other rallies and news conferences.
  The Carbon Free and Healthy Schools campaign is a collaborative partnership between the United Federation of Teachers; DC 37; Service Employees International Union, Local 32BJ; the Building and Construction Trades Council of Greater New York; the New York City Central Labor Council; and Climate Jobs NY to urge federal and local lawmakers to retrofit schools for energy efficiencies, including solar power, to create a safe, healthy, cost-effective school environment while contributing to a greener New York City. The website contains fact sheets, petitions, pledges from community members and Mayor Eric Adams, and press about the campaign.
  The Dial-A-Teacher Program is a joint project of the United Federation of Teachers and the New York City Department of Education. The program provides free homework assistance for parents and elementary and middle school students directly over the telephone. The website contains the phone number for the program, math reference sheets, and images of teachers.
  Also includes United Federation of Teachers' endorsements for mayor, borough presidents, Manhattan district attorney, and comptroller for New York City. UFT endorsed Scott Stringer for mayor in 2021. The website also includes how the endorsement process worked, endorsement videos, and news about the election.
  The Positive Learning Collaborative (PLC) is a partnership between the United Federation of Teachers and NYC Department of Education that provides professional development, comprehensive coaching, and school wide systems and support to all public school staff through restorative practices. Types of professional development they provide include yoga and mindfulness videos and educator and parent workshops. The website also includes information on their sensory tools project, a listing of PLC schools, and news from the partnership.
  United Community Schools is a network of community schools in New York City created by the United Federation of Teachers that works to improve student achievement by addressing the educational, emotional, social and health issues in the way of learning. The website contains the model of the program, list of schools, history of the program, leadership and team, career opportunities, workshops and institutes, consulting resources, planning and implementation materials, information of site visits, results of their work, and news from the network.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued quarterly and semiannually.
  In 2020, https://www.uft.org/ and https://ufthonors.uft.org/ accruals were increased to biweekly and monthly respectively.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of uft.org, ufttc.org, theuftcharterschool.org, carbonfreehealthyschoolsnyc.org, and edwize.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.